Kostadis Roussos: Hello, David.
Kostadis Roussos: Can folks hear me?
Wade: I can hear you, but you're not saying hi to me.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Hi, Wade.
Wade: Hi, Kostadis!
Kostadis Roussos: How are you?
Wade: I'm alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, whenever I say hi to Dave, he's always, like, cheery and says I'm doing fine. Whenever I say hi to you, you bring me down with, like, tales of woe.
Wade: He's a negative person.
David Mendenhall: I can bring you down with Tales of woe.
Kostadis Roussos: But, oh, yeah, but dude, when you bring me down to Tales of woe, then I have to go get alcohol, I have to, like, question the meaning of life.
Wade: Are you saying I need to get better at my downtroddenness? I could take lessons.
Kostadis Roussos: Man, can't you just let somebody have something?
Wade: No. Everybody needs to be as miserable as me all the time.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I meant, let him be better at doing this than you.
Wade: He's got more experience.
David Mendenhall: Russell asks about you all the time, Wade.
Wade: Well, tell him to, you know, come join me at lunch on Thursdays or something. He knows what the, you know, the deal is.
David Mendenhall: I don't think he's gonna join you as much.
Wade: He did once, the day after we all got laid off, like Brutals and me and such. That was a fun day.
Kostadis Roussos: I just want to say something.
Kostadis Roussos: We have varied definitions of the term and understandings of the term fun.
David Mendenhall: Now, Wade was very happy to be laid off.
Wade: No, I was. I was on the way out, and still, they could have let me go for free.
David Mendenhall: It was basically free money that he got that… we could have given him no money and said we gave him extra money.
Wade: Yes.
David Mendenhall: And unemployment, even, so even extra government money.
Wade: Oh yeah, it was great.
David Mendenhall: Yeah?
Wade: No, Caroline thought that it would, you know, entice me to come back in a couple of months, and nope.
David Mendenhall: How is Brutals doing?
Wade: I don't know, I haven't… he's a… he's a… he's always been kind of a mess. He's…
Wade: I think he's still roaming, like, I think he tried living in Austin, and then he had one summer there, and he said, fuck that.
David Mendenhall: It's really hot there.
Wade: Yeah, but he was still coming back here periodically for, like, his dentist, or something. It was just, like, of all the things to come back to the Bay Area for, like…
David Mendenhall: Especially an Englishman to care that much about his dental work.
Wade: Oh, oh, oh, man. No, that's fair. But I haven't heard from him in about a year, it's probably fine, like, I…
Wade: he's, exceedingly private. It's hard to get anything out of him.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, he always was.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, L20, that's what I was looking for.
Wade: Oh yeah, I should probably open up the websites in advance.
David Mendenhall: I know Caroline's gone.
Wade: Yeah, I heard she finally got the axe.
David Mendenhall: She did.
Wade: She, she said… she told me afterward, she's like, hey, I guess I just couldn't play the political game at Roku. I'm like, isn't that your job?
Kostadis Roussos: about, I mean, you talk about, like, reducing people to their essence, and, like, no love, man.
Wade: No, but that's what she told me. She said that, like, she just couldn't keep up with the politics or something, and I'm like, that's… that's director and up, like, that's pretty much all you do, I thought, but…
David Mendenhall: She lasted a couple of years, I mean, she had, like, 5 or 6 good years, and she… I had nothing against her.
David Mendenhall: Once, once Scott was out.
Wade: Oh, Scott? Oh, he left, I assume, right? He didn't get fired, did he?
David Mendenhall: Once Scott was out, that was kind of… she couldn't find her place anymore.
Wade: Yeah, well, that's a shame. Scott was really good.
Wade: Who's in… who's in his position now?
David Mendenhall: Bank attached. Ugh.
Wade: Oh, sorry, no, not Vankitesh, I was thinking Vinayak. I like Vankitesh. Vinayak was… Oh, Vinayak's gone, Vinayak. Oh, thank Christ.
David Mendenhall: I have an eye's gone.
Wade: Oh my god, that guy…
Wade: just, like, stopped me in the middle of a meeting and is like, if it takes 45 milliseconds to go to frame, how can we do 60 frames a second? I'm just like, I don't have the crayons, dude.
David Mendenhall: The crowns, Jesus Christ.
David Mendenhall: He's gone.
Wade: Yeah. Oh, man, I hated him.
Wade: Rom? Rom Marty? No.
David Mendenhall: Jerome's gone.
David Mendenhall: Who?
David Mendenhall: Sheldon's gone.
Wade: A lot of these names, I don't really know. They didn't cross me negatively.
David Mendenhall: Gary?
Kostadis Roussos: I agree.
Wade: Hi, Gary!
Gary Young: Hello!
David Mendenhall: They keep telling me I'm doing a good job, though. No one wants to fire me.
Wade: I think you did fine, you got QT out of the build, that's huge.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the way I look…
Wade: I've done more since then, but that was huge. Like, that was a complete unnecessary dependency.
David Mendenhall: of that.
Kostadis Roussos: I just want to say.
David Mendenhall: Good project.
David Mendenhall: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: If Dave's… if Dave's performance as Vukridine is any indication.
Kostadis Roussos: He… he has definitely mastered the art of naive…
Kostadis Roussos: I'm being able to pretend to not understand politics while playing the game.
Wade: I mean, that is politics.
Kostadis Roussos: I just want to say that.
David Mendenhall: I think Vukradin has decided that he needs to be allies with everyone, because the more allies he has, the more people are gonna come
David Mendenhall: Listen to him play!
David Mendenhall: That sounds interesting. He's happy to have anyone listen to him.
Wade: You know, he could also just make his own family and raise a whole army of audience, or a whole audience, like…
Kostadis Roussos: Wait a second.
David Mendenhall: That.
Kostadis Roussos: That means that… that means that he's aligning with, what's her name? You didn't read my summary, did you?
David Mendenhall: No, no, no, he's thinking… no, at the end of the last session, I was like, yeah, I guess I could go do this thing for Soma. It'd be good to be allies with everybody.
Wade: I mean, I'm just trying to keep balance.
David Mendenhall: I'm like, yeah, let's make allies with everyone, why not?
David Mendenhall: We don't know who's fucking with the Whispering Grove, like, it's… I need money?
David Mendenhall: And I need people to come listen to me play.
Kostadis Roussos: I was just saying that.
David Mendenhall: And I'm not gonna take any unethical money.
Kostadis Roussos: Adabra said that the reason she thought you were, like, one of her kind is because you… you were for the music.
Wade: Oh, she thinks he's an artist.
David Mendenhall: for the fans.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, well, you know, she thought you were for the music, that, that you…
David Mendenhall: We don't have to tell her that.
Gary Young: Wait, are you sure you're for the fans and not the music?
David Mendenhall: I think I might be more for the fans, actually.
Wade: He just wants to be famous without earning it.
Kostadis Roussos: But, but, but, but, but…
Kostadis Roussos: When they listen to the music you want, or when they listen to the music.
David Mendenhall: I know, I know, it's this… it's this character arc I'm going through. Do I want to go pop?
David Mendenhall: Do I want to sell out?
Wade: I like the idea of him challenging.
David Mendenhall: I mean, how much of a sellout am I gonna be?
Wade: I love the idea of him having that struggle.
Kostadis Roussos: He suddenly discovered that when he plays with Brewbarry.
David Mendenhall: Yeah. And I started playing with, Val… what, Valphine, right? And now, like, things are looking up?
Gary Young: Yes, indeed. So now, nice drow.
David Mendenhall: Oh my god!
Gary Young: There's personalities in there.
David Mendenhall: Come on with a drow ally! I don't know, she plays pretty well.
Kostadis Roussos: But hold on, she has her own version of music, it's a combination of lathander, choral music, and…
Gary Young: And.
David Mendenhall: rings in the.
Gary Young: Drow metal, yeah.
Wade: Is that the NUM.
Kostadis Roussos: Lip Maleficum.
Wade: Sounds cursed.
Kostadis Roussos: She doesn't… she's not just into playing drown music. This is… this is a mixture.
Wade: Amazing.
David Mendenhall: pop thing. As long as it's not uneth… it's not unethical to be pop, it's just… The fastest.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, so…
Wade: Is it unethical to sell out… is it unethical to sell out your craft for money, though? Like, or fans?
David Mendenhall: Oh, no, it's just pathetic.
Wade: Okay, okay, that… cool. I'm on board, 100%.
Wade: Did Costatas? No, he's… he's alive.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'm just trying to think right now. Alright.
David Mendenhall: talk to, to Soma's… Soma's Quest.
Wade: So misquised. It's the… it's the whole of Phandalin needs this. This could spread.
David Mendenhall: I'm on board, man. I'm with you, friend.
Gary Young: The trees will pay for our… for our room and board.
David Mendenhall: The Whispering Grove. Adabra, the midwife we saved earlier, asked you to save the Whispering Grove from a magical blight.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Wade: Really, from the interventionist causing said blight.
David Mendenhall: They come to my concerts.
Wade: Maybe, I mean, maybe they're the orcs who attacked us, I don't know.
David Mendenhall: Oh yeah, those guys.
Kostadis Roussos: Who are these… who are these people?
David Mendenhall: Not… I don't know, like.
Wade: We don't know.
Wade: This, this has been extremely, this module or whatever is extremely light on the pre-quest details.
Wade: Like, go fix the lighthouse. What's wrong with it? I don't know, something.
David Mendenhall: Something. You'll find out when you're wrong.
Wade: What's wrong with those points? I don't know, blight.
Gary Young: You know, we could probably ask for more details.
Wade: It did! We don't get it.
David Mendenhall: We're trying to be more on the down-low with.
Kostadis Roussos: Brilliant.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so we decided just to not ask detail, and to just head out, because, because recruiting was all about the conspiracy theories last time.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, still not so sure about Ser Kaelen, and the, the letter did not help. But, I want to be allies with everyone.
David Mendenhall: I want them coming to my concerts.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you know, if he comes to your concert, Adabra comes to your concert, the Zhentarim come to you at the concert, as long…
David Mendenhall: Well, I don't know this entire.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me ask…
David Mendenhall: I don't know.
Kostadis Roussos: If Ukritin is paid by the Zhentarim, does that.
David Mendenhall: I don't… that's stolen money.
Kostadis Roussos: No, is it? You made it, honestly.
Wade: Tom's ours.
Kostadis Roussos: You made… do you know the origin?
David Mendenhall: The Harpers, on the other hand… They're legit.
Gary Young: They're good people.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think I'm gonna get used to this new…
Kostadis Roussos: this new crowd, and after the Harp… after the betrayal of the Harpers.
David Mendenhall: Oh, yeah, right, but that's the previous campaign. That's a different character.
Kostadis Roussos: Different characters. Of course I know.
David Mendenhall: rat.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, actually, an old man who might have looked like Orsik.
Wade: Hmm.
David Mendenhall: Orsik's father.
Wade: Orsik the Wise.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: What was the… alright, I need to open up.
Wade: Something. There it is.
Wade: Where is my… I need to add this, don't I?
Wade: Oh, my staff came alive in the other… goddammit.
Wade: I hate Google Chat.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So… head off to the Whispering Grove.
Kostadis Roussos: And as you approach the Whispering Grove… I need a quick… That's huge.
Kostadis Roussos: Approached the edge of the wish clearing wood.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see, some description here, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, as it… the Whispering Grove looks kind of normal to you. It's kind of like, okay, if you're kind of staring at it, there doesn't seem to be anything…
Kostadis Roussos: odd about it. You don't see any blight.
Kostadis Roussos: It just appears… I'm assuming somebody rolled investigations, insights…
Wade: check.
Kostadis Roussos: You have your new staff, don't forget.
Wade: I do, and I need to… I was actually trying to pull that up. I was gonna ask, I should probably mark it as a tune, shouldn't I?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, and you probably need to put it in… you probably need to mark one attunement spot and cut and paste those attributes I said.
Wade: Right, that's… I was literally in the middle of doing that as you were talking.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's…
Wade: Still, nature check thrown, so, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Nature check throne.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you definitely sense something is very off.
Wade: Guys, something is off.
Kostadis Roussos: that… but you're not quite sure. What you do notice is that
Kostadis Roussos: It is off, but it's not…
Kostadis Roussos: It's… there's not… there's nothing natu… there's something…
David Mendenhall: Is it a treat?
Gary Young: It's, like, green and too few spots.
Kostadis Roussos: So let me ask you a question. Are you… do you tend towards the naturalist side? So, since you tend towards the naturalist side, to be quite honest, you don't really notice anything that is off. You're kind of surprised that
Kostadis Roussos: Soma would… that Adabra would say it's, that it would say it's, there's some kind of blight.
Wade: So it just… it's just more of a vague sense of unease, and not any, like, clear signs of, like, rotting trees, or…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you're just kind of like… you do sense a blight, but you're… you don't see it anywhere.
Gary Young: all this weird green in the overt bright, you know, like, there's not even all that much, like, slime around. I mean, like, it's really weird.
Wade: Trees thrive in light, right?
Wade: Like you! Like you, Valphine.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't think you understand the concept of what Valphine does if you think she thrives in light.
Wade: Well, she enjoys the pain.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, gloriously painful one. That's right.
Wade: I mean, that's a type of thriving.
Kostadis Roussos: The thing I've been wondering is, does Vilphine, like, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: Is she, like, a… why has she not resorted to the stabbing herself and healing herself? Is there some… I was kind of…
Gary Young: Wait, you just… you don't think she does that? You think she doesn't do that?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know if she does.
David Mendenhall: It's like a party trick before bed each night.
Gary Young: I deliberately made sure that she was quite pierced.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see, I need a battle map. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, this will do fine.
Wade: Discern Corruption. Hello!
Wade: Sorry, now as I'm cutting and pasting everything in,
Wade: May as well throw that into the mix.
Wade: Alright, can I mark… I don't know how to mark this attuned. Might just have to remember that in my head.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, come on.
Wade: What now?
Kostadis Roussos: I think I'm just trying to find a monster, and it's not, like… Animal.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, fine. I'll just have to drop the token in here, sorry, my bad.
Wade: What the heck is going on?
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Wade: Oh, jeez.
Kostadis Roussos: So, biggering…
Wade: We're still on the world map.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, I know.
Wade: Oh, I'm sorry, sometimes you forget.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that's fair, that's fair, but thank you for… thank you for reminding me.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So now I will… okay.
David Mendenhall: Can you tell me where on the world map we entered?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you entered into the Withering Woods.
David Mendenhall: Okay. Oh, right, I remember it was marked on there.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so if you see where you guys are, like, there's a little red thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Red lettering?
Wade: the Whispering Grove records.
David Mendenhall: to handling, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Springwoods.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Ms. Ringwoods.
David Mendenhall: Very near.
Kostadis Roussos: Just, yeah. Okay, so…
David Mendenhall: Looks like it's, like, a one-hour hike from Panama.
Kostadis Roussos: one hour hike.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a… it's an area of wooded area, not… it's called the Whispering Grove, it's, you know, kind of, like, between valleys and whatnot. It's kind of a weird, sort of, dense forest area.
David Mendenhall: And there's a stat here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, but let me give it to the description, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Does anybody have, Speak with Animals?
Wade: I do. Of course I do.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the stag certainly is standing in front of you.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Yeah, no, this is probably me, unless it's another Krabby that can talk.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: Nope, all you, man.
Wade: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And I'm just gonna show you…
Wade: I forget, can I…
Kostadis Roussos: Aw, such a pretty boy. What you notice is that the flag… it's a majestic stag, except its fur is shimmering, flickering, that phases in and out.
Kostadis Roussos: As you look at… as you look… roll a nature check? Perception check? Nature or Perception? Whichever, whichever… Nature, Insight, Investigation, Arcana, whichever ones you want.
Gary Young: 19.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Oh, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: do note…
Wade: 23…
David Mendenhall: Even better.
Kostadis Roussos: assume?
Wade: This is my wheelhouse.
Kostadis Roussos: Soma… Soma has… Soma has discovered that
Kostadis Roussos: This stag is caught between dimensions.
Wade: That can't be good.
Gary Young: No.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Gary Young: I didn't true.
David Mendenhall: Links, insert.
Kostadis Roussos: All of a sudden, It flickers…
Kostadis Roussos: And she also notices that its antlers are kind of, like, embedded in… you know, like, those four-dimensional things that are embedded in three-dimensional space?
Wade: Oh, like the hypercube, you mean? Where it's, like, it's constantly changing a 3D shape?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so it's constantly changing. It's.
Wade: Presence in our universe.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Wade: Or our plane, or whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: And it teleports 15 feet.
Wade: Okay, I don't think I need a staff to detect an unnatural blight here.
Wade: I, I think that. That is unnatural.
David Mendenhall: Hey, do you want to talk to this tag?
Wade: I do want to talk to the stag. So I burned a spell slot.
Kostadis Roussos: Howdy.
Wade: You're gonna burn a sliced balsa? Okay. Well, I assume, I mean, I…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, just give me a second.
Wade: Oh, we have long rested, I assume, since the last thing my.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, yeah, everybody's long-rested.
Wade: There we go, but I did.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you did. Yes, you did.
Wade: Hello?
David Mendenhall: Sorry.
David Mendenhall: Wrong button.
Wade: Stop!
David Mendenhall: Stop trying to kill everything.
Kostadis Roussos: What did he try?
David Mendenhall: That was the wrong button.
Wade: Scrolled initiative.
David Mendenhall: Turn off my drag or something, but I…
Kostadis Roussos: Just talk!
David Mendenhall: Talk to him, put them away.
Kostadis Roussos: Chill, man, chill. Go play some music. So you… so, okay, so how does that speak with animals work?
Wade: For the duration, I can comprehend and verbally communicate with beasts, and, can use any influence action skill on them.
Wade: Most beats are really boring and have nothing to say, but at minimum, the beats can give you information.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so the Beast sort of says, okay, so,
Kostadis Roussos: What is it that you would like to ask the beast?
Wade: Are you okay? I think I'm just more concerned about its welfare, watching it do this,
Wade: Sort of bizarre existence.
Kostadis Roussos: It pauses and goes… I was okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Until you walked into my territory.
Kostadis Roussos: Why are you in my territory? Get out of my territory.
Wade: We're just passing through, we mean no harm, we just… we notice that you seem… Out of sorts.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know what you mean. I'm completely… I am completely… and he's… so the stag sort of looks at you and sort of…
Kostadis Roussos: You can roll an insight to see where the boundaries of its territory are.
Wade: I can try… let's see… where is… it's under I, wouldn't it be? Yes.
Wade: And I think… do I get advantage on that as well? You got it, man. 15? Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: I get insight on wisdom checks in natural territories, which this would… or advantage on…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it would be, then this would be.
Wade: Yeah, let's go ahead and toss it again. It's a wisdom-based roll, so there we go, so I got a 20 now.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so you're definitely able to identify…
David Mendenhall: Tonight.
Wade: This is a Soma quest, it's gonna be easy for her.
David Mendenhall: We're all just along for the ride, man.
Wade: Kind of. We'll try to make it quick.
David Mendenhall: I got my daggers.
Wade: Which side of the boundary is his, the north or the south? The side he's on. Well, he didn't start there, he teleported there.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, he started… no, you know, that's true, he… but it's because you guys, like, you know, he's got his boundary, so you tell your…
Wade: Brewbarry, can you back off a little? Just, you know… This guy, he's.
David Mendenhall: Brew, come on over here.
Wade: Brooked, could you back up a little? Just give the stag some privacy.
Gary Young: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: There. There. Alright.
Wade: We've cleared your territory, is there,
Wade: Something weird going on, though? I'm not used to seeing stags teleport around and shimmer like you do.
Kostadis Roussos: The stag, goes.
Kostadis Roussos: Looks at this.
Gary Young: Looks and goes…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh!
Kostadis Roussos: And then he teleports again, and he leaves an afterimage behind where he was. Sorry, I forgot to mention that last time. So he sort of leaves an… it's like a…
Kostadis Roussos: It's…
Gary Young: Splacer Beast.
David Mendenhall: Yes. Yeah, link dog.
Wade: Blink tag, blank stag.
Kostadis Roussos: Then after, like, a few seconds, it disappears.
Wade: Huh? Huh? Huh?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, I… I… I am, he goes, hmm…
Kostadis Roussos: I do… I must… this is very… we… he does pause and says, Yes, things have not been normal for some time.
Wade: Come on over and just kind of follow him around his edge of the cage.
Wade: time. Do you have any vague idea how much time? And what do you mean by things have not been normal?
Kostadis Roussos: I used to just be able to walk and prance and eat the vegetables.
Kostadis Roussos: And now I can blink, and my horns are… Different.
Kostadis Roussos: My antlers are different.
Wade: They're different every time I look at them.
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly! Do you know how difficult it is to go through the forest with your antlers?
Kostadis Roussos: I, I tried to…
Wade: I wouldn't know, I don't have antlers.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, imagine if you had a shell that changed shape all the time.
Wade: Oh, Bruce!
Kostadis Roussos: It would just be awkward.
Wade: It would, it would. Do you remember anything weird happening that led to all this? Did you, like, drink some weird water, eat some mushrooms? Like…
Kostadis Roussos: No, the whole forest has gotten weird. It's almost as if everything has changed.
Wade: Hmm.
Wade: That's what they tell us in town as well, that things have gotten a little strange out here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, everything has changed.
Kostadis Roussos: It pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: I… he then pauses and goes, but… but… but… he looks at you and says, do you have anything to eat?
Wade: God, what a one gift for some good berries.
Wade: Do we have anything in our inventory for a stag?
Wade: Do we have some octopus or something?
David Mendenhall: We have some green mushroom rations.
Gary Young: Yeah, Shark Beat.
David Mendenhall: Purple.
Wade: Oh, if I forget, our dear…
David Mendenhall: incrementable mushrooms.
Wade: Yeah, deer… well, those could turn into potions, right? Did we…
David Mendenhall: And shark meat.
Kostadis Roussos: I think he's an herbivore, right?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, he's an herbivore. Go with the green spectrum rations.
Wade: Yeah, yeah, have some mushroom rations.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. So the deer says, well, it all started in the center of the forest.
Wade: In the center.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes…
David Mendenhall: He points you in the general rough direction. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he says, And there were some other nice people who came here.
Kostadis Roussos: You should… yes.
Wade: What… describe them? What did they do? Who were they? What did they look like?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, they… there was a…
Wade: He probably doesn't like it.
Kostadis Roussos: There was a… there was a… they were very nice, and they spoke to me, too.
Wade: We Druids do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes!
Wade: It's a party trick.
Kostadis Roussos: See, they spoke to me, too, and they asked.
Kostadis Roussos: And everything started to… and they said they would fix it.
Kostadis Roussos: But they haven't.
Wade: Do you know how they tried? Did you give them any pointers to fixing it?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I… I was… I was too busy eating and, you know, trying to tell them to get out of my… my home.
Wade: What are the odds that the problem is inside your territory, and we might need to come look in?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, why don't you go to the center first, and if it's not there, you can come… and you can come back.
Wade: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Or you could try to persuade him to, or you could try to persuade him.
Wade: I think… I think it's fine to check the center first and come check back. He's probably not going far.
Kostadis Roussos: How far are we from the center?
Kostadis Roussos: A few survival checks away.
Kostadis Roussos: God.
Wade: Monster.
Wade: That's alright, advantage on all of those.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, right.
Wade: Alright, then I guess we trek on towards the center.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Crushed it.
Wade: I got you, fam.
Kostadis Roussos: What'd you get?
Wade: 23.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, here we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: You see a dense thicket of brambles with leaves that pulse with a natural color, sometimes glowing, sometimes withering to black.
David Mendenhall: Torch them.
Wade: That might actually be the legit cause, er, case here.
Wade: I don't know, I may as well burn the one chip.
David Mendenhall: This is along the way, along the way.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, so let me just…
Wade: Oh, this isn't the center yet, this is the first survival check.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: Meh.
Kostadis Roussos: This is… yes, here, there's a,
Kostadis Roussos: There's a dense thicket of… okay.
Gary Young: Nobody has Fireball yet, dude.
Kostadis Roussos: No, nobody has fireballs.
David Mendenhall: No, but we have… We have smaller fires.
Wade: I mean, we could just do it the old school, right? Like, just a regular old fire. It's not like it's combat.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah.
Wade: Any… anything to be discerned from them? I mean, like, I assume they look quite unnatural, like…
Wade: Yeah, I finally blew a roll.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so did you… did you try to discern something?
Wade: Well, I tried to do a nature check on it as, you know, they're brambles, aren't they?
Kostadis Roussos: Here we go. It looked like that. So you did a nature check.
Wade: They look like that ICN on things.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, we don't see anything.
Wade: Wait, there we go, I see.
Kostadis Roussos: Whoa!
Wade: They look like giant anuses made of branches.
Kostadis Roussos: So, again, there's, like, sort of, like, a bizarre…
Kostadis Roussos: sort of quality to them that makes them look somewhat less than nor… like, they're… again, at this point in time, you… you're correctly discerning that whatever this blight may or may not be, there seems to be some sort of…
Kostadis Roussos: Planar… leakage, bleeding, like, this is not…
Wade: Yeah, that's not normal.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and as you approach within 10 feet, it strikes you.
Wade: Oh, good. Good, good, good. Let's go.
David Mendenhall: Upside down.
David Mendenhall: You were gonna torch it, right?
Wade: Well, I was gonna go up and expect it, and I got whacked, so yeah, I think they needed to get burned.
Wade: Do I just have to… defense or anything? What happens?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, hold on.
Wade: Oh, sure.
Wade: Do the rambles grapple me?
Kostadis Roussos: Let's just roll for… let's roll for initiative.
Wade: We're literally fighting a thicket.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Alright, switch tabs… Soma's at 12… Alright, so what I got?
Wade: No, 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Hey, where'd just go?
Kostadis Roussos: Pick it.
Wade: You're really gonna call it a thicket?
Kostadis Roussos: And I don't think I needed… I need to call it something, right?
Wade: No, I think it's fine, I think it's appropriate, I just…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, alright.
Wade: Next up, you know, Magic Missile the Darkness or something.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, there. Okay.
Gary Young: Is there just one ticket?
David Mendenhall: 16…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it's just one big thicket, 52 hit points.
Wade: 12. And me with a blunt weapon.
David Mendenhall: You got an initiative for the thicket?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that rolls with, gets no bonuses, so whatever… it should be a zero.
Wade: It has no bonus?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I mean, to dexterity.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that just sounded awful.
David Mendenhall: I think it will not get to attack, is my prediction. Alright, Valphine.
Gary Young: Alright, she can start with, probably, Sacred Flame. That seems appropriate.
David Mendenhall: Seems like a good choice.
Wade: Isn't it technically radiant, but still fine, like…
Gary Young: Technically Radiance.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Gary Young: But, it… It does damage save DC13.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I need to roll. Has no bonuses, because again, like I said, doesn't have any dexterity.
Gary Young: No bonus or a negative bonus?
Kostadis Roussos: No bonus. Made it save.
Wade: Three dodges.
David Mendenhall: What is…
Kostadis Roussos: Now, actually what happens is suddenly the plane shifts just enough.
Wade: Oh, yeah.
Gary Young: It's planar shifting, dodging. Okay, yeah, alright.
Wade: That, that, that tracks.
Gary Young: That works.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, it wasn't so much it was, but the whole environment sort of shifts. It itself doesn't do anything.
Wade: But we're just, like, stable through all of this, right?
Kostadis Roussos: So far.
Wade: So far, oh boy.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Gary Young: So, Brewbarry will move in closer, and then…
Kostadis Roussos: Does he move in within 10 feet?
Wade: To exactly 10 feet.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, cool, just wondering, just checking.
Gary Young: Cause he doesn't have to be closer.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Wade: Because he's got Reach, or whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he's got… he's got the all-important reach.
Gary Young: Let's see, why is this not giving me a… Attack… Pop-up thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Okay, so… it… you are, in fact…
Kostadis Roussos: Attacked by a… some thorny tendrils.
Gary Young: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, so much should have been attacked by thorny trendles.
Wade: Well, yeah, I thought that was how the combat started.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so I forgot to do that.
Wade: Yeah, go ahead and roll one on me.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay, plus 4 to hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Aren't you glad I blew that on my, saving throw?
Wade: Yes, I did not want to be crit… oh, wow, that still sucks. That's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, You take 7 points of damage.
Wade: Alright. And you take…
Kostadis Roussos: You take 7 points of piercing damage, plus 3 necrotic.
Kostadis Roussos: And you must also make a DC-12 Constitution saving throw, or be poisoned.
Wade: Constipation… alright. And there we go. Alright, I get poisoned.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Alright. That means you have disadvantage on some things.
Wade: On some things, alright.
Gary Young: 20…
Wade: Poisland.
Wade: Alright, back to Brewbarry then.
Gary Young: I do not understand why, but it appears that Virtual Tabletop does not like… Beyond 20 does not like to have,
Gary Young: more than one… Character open.
Gary Young: It's weird.
Wade: Wrong.
Gary Young: It's not letting me just roll the, weapon attack.
Wade: Are you sure the mod just didn't…
Wade: Disconnect? No, you've rolled other things, yeah.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay. Well, I will do this very manually.
Kostadis Roussos: There, I, I, there, the poison condition, there for us all to see.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade: A lot of us are getting poisoned, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Gary Young: So I assume that's a hat.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, a DC12. A DC, whatever I put there, 12, yes.
Wade: Yeah.
Gary Young: Plus… Six… Sorry, it should be 1D… 12 plus 6.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: 1D10 plus 6.
Gary Young: Ugh.
Wade: And you weren't raging or anything, right?
Gary Young: with Raging. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, 16 points of damage. Could you mark that down, or I'll mark it down.
Gary Young: I will do that. Thank you. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Soma.
Wade: Yeah, this isn't gonna…
Kostadis Roussos: Poison Condition runs out at the end of your turn, just so you know.
Wade: Oh, it's literally just one round?
Wade: Well, either way, we're going to, Wild Shape. Get me the bear icon when you get a chance.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, bear icon.
Wade: That's gonna be worth a burned, slot.
Wade: And then… sorry, I have disadvantages.
Wade: politics. Huh? We're at large brown barrier.
Kostadis Roussos: Go ahead.
Wade: Or just brown.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I know what it is. We had the giant toad Soma, but we haven't done the Giant Toad…
Wade: I've done Bear before, I've done Bear plenty of time.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I don't know, this is just me… this is me whining to myself, not to you.
Gary Young: There we go.
Kostadis Roussos: Could be a brown bear.
Wade: Once I use the fourth shape, you're gonna have to keep me honest.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, nameplate… Soma.
Kostadis Roussos: There's… Can be controlled by all players. Save changes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's good. Changes. Alright, there you go.
Kostadis Roussos: One Soma Brown Bear.
Wade: Alright. Multi-attack, but it's gonna be disadvantage, so there's gonna be 2 misses, I'm sure.
Wade: Let's go. Public rule…
Gary Young: Why?
Wade: Yep, that's a miss, and then the multi-second… That's a hit.
David Mendenhall: The hit? 14 hits?
Kostadis Roussos: Is that… what is it, piercing or slashing?
Wade: Slashing.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so that's, that's real damage.
Wade: That should be real damage, so 26 now.
Kostadis Roussos: Muchardin?
David Mendenhall: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Alright, let's start… with… And then poison is expired.
Wade: now, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Alright, unsettling words, roll a 1D6. Creature must subtract the number rolled from the next saving throw it makes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: 2, so it's got a minus 2 on its savings card.
Kostadis Roussos: You say creature? Because it's a plant.
David Mendenhall: Mmm.
Gary Young: Why is a plant not a creature?
David Mendenhall: A plant, not a creature.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that's a good question. Is a plant a creature?
David Mendenhall: I mean, I think creature is, like, a generic term. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: They are creatures.
David Mendenhall: object. It's not like a pedestal.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, that's… I… I… yes, I…
David Mendenhall: It's not a gazebo.
Kostadis Roussos: Dude…
Wade: It could be turned into a gazebo.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, I know what a gazebo is. I've told you the gazebo… I've told you about my son and the gazebo story, right?
David Mendenhall: Yes, many times.
Wade: Not me, but we'll save it for another day.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I'll bore you at another time.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so, minus 2…
Wade: Do you mock them?
David Mendenhall: Mock the plants. DC13 Wisdom save?
David Mendenhall: Actually, the word GC15.
Wade: Oh, because he's got, yeah, minus 2.
David Mendenhall: Got a minus 2, so equivalent of a DC15.
Kostadis Roussos: Is it a Wisdom? Oh my god, so that's, like, my… that's a 19 or a 20.
David Mendenhall: Well, 10% chance.
Wade: Yeah, you blew that.
David Mendenhall: A.
Wade: Minus…
David Mendenhall: You take 4 damage, and you have disadvantage on your attack.
Kostadis Roussos: I never thought of a creature like this having disadvantage.
David Mendenhall: Okay, you now have… I'll take the 4 off.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, regenerates for 5 hit points.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so 27?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
David Mendenhall: And then I assume it's going to try to attack?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: It's just a bear, I belong here, don't mess with me.
David Mendenhall: Okay, but it has disadvantage.
Kostadis Roussos: Sure.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: will… The bear… the bear is… so I guess it'll probably go after.
Wade: Oh, I was just joking, but sure.
Wade: I don't look out of place.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, no, you don't, because you shifted in your planar sensibilities, Let's see, I will…
Kostadis Roussos: The only two targets are Brewbarry and, and… Alright, Brewbarry it is.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, it does two attacks, so it'll attack twice.
David Mendenhall: First one is disadvantaged, second is normal, then.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so… we will… First one is 2D20…
Gary Young: Keep low one.
Gary Young: Beyond 20 is definitely not working for me anymore.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh no.
David Mendenhall: That's a…
Wade: Bummer.
Kostadis Roussos: plus 4.
Kostadis Roussos: Another one of my friends who's playing Dungeons & Dragons… oh, this might explain why another one of my friends was having a problem.
Kostadis Roussos: When they had two character sheets open, the one of the two did not… the attack rolls did not work.
David Mendenhall: Oh, because he has Brewbarry and Valphine.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Wade: That's weird, like, I have… well, I don't have two character sheets open, I have a monster sheet and a character sheet, and they both work.
Gary Young: I've had two open in the past, and it works fine.
Kostadis Roussos: No, this has definitely been a new behavior that I've seen with my cousin.
Gary Young: And right now, I'm getting no buttons on either character, after reloading the tabs.
David Mendenhall: Wow.
Gary Young: Including logging into Roll20 again.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you try uninstalling the device, the thing, and reinstalling it?
Wade: The extension, yeah.
Gary Young: Yeah, I can do that.
David Mendenhall: So you got a 10… a 10 on the first one, that's a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
David Mendenhall: Alright, second attack.
Kostadis Roussos: And then the second attack is on Zoma.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, now it's on Brewbarry, because it's kind of mindless that way.
Kostadis Roussos: 13, I think that's a miss, right?
Wade: Also a miss. It's a miss on either one of us.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: Back to the top.
Kostadis Roussos: Gosh.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Valphine.
Gary Young: Alright, assume that we're gonna do this, Sacred Flame again?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: The deck's safe.
Gary Young: Yup.
David Mendenhall: I can, oh, no.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm older 70.
Wade: Yeah, it's really good at dodging sacred flames through its plainerness.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, it is.
Wade: Yeah, yeah, we see it.
Gary Young: Oh, okay, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled a 17.
Gary Young: Alright then.
Gary Young: Next, I guess we got Brewbarry?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. And the button is not showing up.
Gary Young: Dang it.
Gary Young: And reload this, character sheet, and see if it does it now.
Gary Young: No. Okay, well…
Wade: Two different browsers.
Gary Young: Whatever.
Wade: Panking.
Gary Young: I have it here.
Gary Young: What the heck was that?
Gary Young: Next thing we'll do is we're gonna reach for the dice.
Gary Young: Crits. Okay.
Gary Young: Alright, so… we do… 2010… Plus 6, and then…
Gary Young: I have another D10 for crit.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: And then my strength damage is not… not added twice, is that correct?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that is correct.
Gary Young: Okay, so… 17, and I assume I don't get to cleave, because it's still one creature, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, it's one creature, alright?
David Mendenhall: Alright, it's down to 10.
Wade: Alright, I got this.
Wade: I think.
David Mendenhall: Bring it home, bear.
Wade: Let's go! Just gonna roll them both without looking.
David Mendenhall: That's a mess.
Wade: That's 14 damage, that'll finish it.
David Mendenhall: That'll do it.
Kostadis Roussos: Nice. Alright.
David Mendenhall: Good job, team.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, it temporarily…
Wade: Yeah, it's gonna regenerate, isn't it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, if you want to go past it, you should go past it now.
Wade: Yeah, I get that sense, we should continue our trek.
David Mendenhall: Should we, set it on fire as we go?
Wade: Yeah, I think that's worth doing. Well, you don't want to burn down the whole forest, like, how… how much kindling is around it?
Gary Young: As a forest, I assume there's plenty of kindling.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Yeah, I'd really like not to burn down the whole forest fire. You don't want to start a forest fire? No, no, I'm not a…
David Mendenhall: I think Adabra would say, if we… I think she would consider us interventionists at that point.
Gary Young: We rescued the Whispering Grove.
David Mendenhall: We rescued the Whispering Grove. It didn't survive the rescuing, but we rescued it.
Wade: Yeah, I think Adabra would not be pleased. You're gonna have to let me know how much time passes, because I have an hour in bear form, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay, alright.
David Mendenhall: going to the center of the forest is not going to take an hour. Only took us an hour to get to the… Right, right.
Wade: But I'm just informing the GM.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, thank you for that, alright.
Wade: Another survival check, I assume?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Wade: Oh, wow.
David Mendenhall: Well, you're not the only one in the party, you know.
Wade: Yeah, somebody… I've been… I can't do this as a bear, apparently.
Kostadis Roussos: Vukradin is quite convinced.
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry! Brewbarry! Brewbarry! Valphine! Valphine! Valphine!
David Mendenhall: Okay! Yay!
Wade: I don't know that any of those are good enough.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, actually, that was… that was blueberries, not Velfinus.
David Mendenhall: Oh, yeah, he's got two breweries.
Gary Young: That… that one… last one was supposed to be,
Gary Young: the Valphine with a plus 3.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, we just… no, we saw…
David Mendenhall: I would have gotten a 13, so a 13.
Gary Young: They both showed up as Brewbarry with the same Brewbarry bonus, that's what I thought.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry… so, so, Valphine, so you're not at a point of conflict where Vukradin is quite convinced he knows which way to go.
Kostadis Roussos: anything.
Kostadis Roussos: Does he defer to Valphine A?
David Mendenhall: I just… I just know that, like, I… I don't… I don't discern the correct path.
Kostadis Roussos: How's that?
Gary Young: Yeah.
Wade: And apparently, I lost my senses as a bear.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, okay. Alright, so you avoid getting lost.
Kostadis Roussos: And, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You, as you're walking through the forest, you hear distant howls which echo unnaturally, sometimes overlapping or out of sync with the environment.
Wade: Yeah, guys, this is kinda creepy.
Gary Young: It's nice.
David Mendenhall: It's.
Gary Young: Runs me of home.
David Mendenhall: It's like the Blair Witch, dude.
Wade: Oh, nothing's gonna happen, and everybody's gonna get pissed and walk out of the theater? Like…
David Mendenhall: Oh, what?
Kostadis Roussos: Dude, that's not…
David Mendenhall: I liked that movie.
Kostadis Roussos: You did?
Wade: I did. There's nothing wrong with it, I'm just joking.
David Mendenhall: It does take a lot of hate, though.
Wade: Anyway, so we hear this echoing…
David Mendenhall: Weird cacophony.
Wade: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
David Mendenhall: They all died!
David Mendenhall: Nothing's gonna happen.
David Mendenhall: Every single one of them.
Gary Young: They die off-camera, though, right?
David Mendenhall: Yeah. Camera.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so as you're bouncing around, A dire wolf.
Gary Young: alternative working.
Gary Young: Good.
David Mendenhall: A dire wolf.
Wade: Oh, man, why'd I do bear instead of wolf?
Kostadis Roussos: Because you…
Kostadis Roussos: And…
Wade: I think, how long does Speak with Landon must last?
Kostadis Roussos: At 10 minutes, I checked it. More than 10 minutes… 10 minutes have elapsed.
Wade: Christ, so I can't talk to him.
Wade: Without tossing a spell slot.
Wade: That's just a family, right? We don't need to mess with a family.
David Mendenhall: It's a family of wolves, or it's a singular wolf?
Wade: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: It's, it's a dire wolf with, 6 wolves.
Wade: I only see 5, which is terrifying enough. There's the 6th.
Wade: Do they look like, you know.
Wade: I'm about to… I'm about to give you that. I'm about to show you a picture. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I had fun putting this adventure, I hope you guys are at least creeped by it.
David Mendenhall: Only on Fireball.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, this, this… I went through this whole campaign…
David Mendenhall: Fireball was made for. This exact encounter.
Kostadis Roussos: Appreciate it.
Kostadis Roussos: That is true.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Gary Young: Cleave.
David Mendenhall: I dropped all my… I dropped my area of effect spell.
Kostadis Roussos: You did?
David Mendenhall: Regretting that, I did.
Wade: Oh, did you have an area of sleep or something?
David Mendenhall: I do have sleep, yeah. Sleep's not as powerful as it used to be, though.
Kostadis Roussos: It's powerful in different ways, though.
Wade: I mean, if you could sleep, like, 4 of the little wolflings, it'd be fine, like…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you should see these wolves here.
Wade: Yeah, that doesn't look good.
Kostadis Roussos: Goodness.
David Mendenhall: Role for initiative.
Wade: Hold on!
Wade: We can't talk to them?
David Mendenhall: I don't like being attacked. 18.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Alright.
Wade: He's just going guns blazing. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so the wool.
David Mendenhall: We gotta save this grove for Adabra!
Wade: We can't just murder everything.
David Mendenhall: to my concert.
David Mendenhall: She can bring the emerald Enclave.
Wade: Alright, alright, alright, where's my, some, initiative from her?
Wade: Come on, roll.
Wade: Oh, jeez, what a time to roll a 20.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you roll some… did you roll a 20?
Wade: I rolled a 20 on initiative. I did not want to.
Kostadis Roussos: It's probably not something you wanted.
Wade: Huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Let's see, I can't cast much except, like, Moonbeam in animal form, can I?
David Mendenhall: Boonbeam's useful.
Wade: It is, but it's…
Gary Young: I have a trick up my sleeve, too.
David Mendenhall: so do I.
Wade: I'm just trying to figure out, like, what I… yeah, I think that's the only thing I can… Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Alright, Wolf2.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the wolves… How was the pack?
Wade: Oh, woo!
Kostadis Roussos: As they… as they approach you, they howl as a pack, and everyone must make a saving throw against fear… against,
Kostadis Roussos: A wisdom saving throw.
David Mendenhall: Wisdom.
Wade: I'm gonna call it that as a natural and natural environment.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Wade: That was a good time.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: So, just if anybody's frightened, tell me.
David Mendenhall: Oh, okay.
Wade: Vucher didn't look scared.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the… I put the broker in the…
Gary Young: So does… Does this interface with… Rage in some way?
Kostadis Roussos: What do you mean, interface?
Gary Young: Does rage and fear… Interact in some way?
Kostadis Roussos: This, no, I don't think so.
David Mendenhall: Is Brewbarry afraid? I don't see his role.
Gary Young: No, I was, I didn't.
Kostadis Roussos: At 6, okay, to answer your question, at 6th level, you can't be charmed or frightened while raging.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade: Quite level 6 yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, so it does intersect, but not at this level.
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Did anybody get affected? Only Lukri didn'.
David Mendenhall: Vukradin.
Wade: Which is fine, you don't need to move closer.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Okay.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Wolf2.
Kostadis Roussos: Wolf2.
Kostadis Roussos: Both two rushes in.
Kostadis Roussos: And… Let's see what their movement is… Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Armor class, well, my feet, 40 feet, okay, so he rushes… He rushes at Vukradin.
Kostadis Roussos: Takes a bite of you.
David Mendenhall: disadvantage, I assume.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, man.
David Mendenhall: Only if I attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, it has a… it bites you.
David Mendenhall: Doesn't it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, our AC16?
David Mendenhall: Okay, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And… if… let me just make sure I got this right…
David Mendenhall: Let's not do very much damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, if… are you a medium or smaller creature?
David Mendenhall: Medium.
Kostadis Roussos: are knocked prone.
David Mendenhall: Okay, how much damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, yes, 5 points of damage.
David Mendenhall: I'm not moving anyway, it's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Oh, you.
David Mendenhall: Alright, Soma.
Wade: Yeah, well, may as well try to protect a little bit, so…
David Mendenhall: Focus on the… focus on the dire wolf.
Wade: Yeah, well, I'm gonna put down a moonbeam in front of everyone, so…
David Mendenhall: Oh, yeah, that works.
Wade: Yeah, so I need a 5-foot radius circle, probably around there.
Wade: It is… semi-permanent.
Wade: And so those guys are going to take, I should cast…
David Mendenhall: You can move the beam each round, right?
Wade: Yes, so that's why I said it's, like, semi-permanent.
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: What is the… what is… how big is it?
Wade: It's 5 foot radius, so 10 feet wide, so it can at least hit these two, but it's not gonna.
Kostadis Roussos: Should be able to move that.
Wade: I can, first try, excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: Thanks, baby.
Kostadis Roussos: You should actually… should actually see it in… in the sidebar thing, the side thing. Should say Area of Effect Templates when you click on the little magic book.
Wade: Let me double check. I've seen this before, but I didn't know I could pull stuff out.
David Mendenhall: Magic.
Wade: Oh, yeah, can I delete that? Alright, I guess, I guess I didn't need you for that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just saying next time you can just do that.
Wade: Yeah, anyway, so that's the moonbeam that's down there. Those guys take…
Wade: The damage I chucked, which I have misplaced, and Constitution Save, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Great, Constitution saving grill.
Kostadis Roussos: The wolf… Blows it.
Kostadis Roussos: And dies.
Wade: They're that low… oh, I didn't even look at their HP.
David Mendenhall: 11 points.
Kostadis Roussos: That's… they're not particularly… that's not particularly challenging combat.
Kostadis Roussos: D20… The other… the other guy makes it, so he takes 5 points.
Wade: Yeah.
Wade: Alright, 5 points on Big Daddy, 32.
Wade: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Alright, Valphine, you're up.
Wade: I'm actually gonna… sorry, I'm gonna move up to give a little cover to people, too.
Kostadis Roussos: That should be 22, I don't know why it says 30.
Kostadis Roussos: 2, should be 22.
Kostadis Roussos: For the dire wolf.
David Mendenhall: Okay, Direwolf's down to 22 hit points.
Kostadis Roussos: No, he started off with 22, so he's down to 17.
Wade: Oh, okay, so he's 22, and we did 5 to hit 17. Oh, this is nothing, this is just… that was a waste of a spell.
David Mendenhall: Alright. No, it's good. It's good use. It's good. Valphine.
Wade: I'm gonna mold that.
Gary Young: So she moves here.
Gary Young: And then to cast Fairy Fire on all 5 of those guys.
David Mendenhall: You don't need to do that.
Wade: They're… they're 11 hit points.
Gary Young: Fine.
Wade: I mean, you can, it's just…
Gary Young: Okay, just as a side note…
Kostadis Roussos: You can't cast spells while you're in wild shape.
Wade: You can cast Moonbeam when you're in Wild Shape.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I did not know that.
Wade: Right at the bottom, it says in bright red, like.
David Mendenhall: It says that right at the bottom of the spell.
Kostadis Roussos: Fair enough.
Gary Young: Huh? That's an exception, huh?
Wade: It is a Circle of the Moon spell, which is the specialization.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay, okay, okay, okay, yeah.
Wade: That is the only spell I can cast in Wild Shape.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
David Mendenhall: I like it.
Kostadis Roussos: blanket.
Gary Young: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's next?
Gary Young: Anyway, I'm gonna still ferry fire, all those guys.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Gary Young: Yeah, DC13 DeckSafe.
Kostadis Roussos: So.
Gary Young: Tell me which ones succeed.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The only ones that fail are… 1 and… Everybody else.
David Mendenhall: 1 and 6 failed, and… 4 or 5 different succeeding.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
David Mendenhall: Good phenomenon.
Gary Young: For me.
Kostadis Roussos: I rolled well.
David Mendenhall: I will… Drop asleep.
David Mendenhall: On those 3 guys there.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, could you… can I give you another one?
David Mendenhall: That'd be nice. Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: You can also pull your own if you want, you can have different colors.
David Mendenhall: Where the, I don't know, you met this magic book you talked about.
Gary Young: Yeah, I was looking for the book, too. I couldn't find it.
Wade: It's the… on the right, it's the third icon after the… it's chat, then a palette, then a magic book.
Wade: Topright.
David Mendenhall: I see it.
Gary Young: Oh, and this is where you have the.
David Mendenhall: Oh, there it is.
Gary Young: party characters, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, like, that's where all the party characters… you should even see your bear icon there.
Wade: I do.
Kostadis Roussos: Some of the Barisoma spiders.
David Mendenhall: It's snapping… That's not working. Snapping to the grid, though.
David Mendenhall: Can I, like, remove snap to grid?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you hit Alt and then place it wherever you want.
David Mendenhall: Oh, Alt, oh, alt.
David Mendenhall: Never.
Kostadis Roussos: That won't… that will… okay, so the rule is 50%, that's not 50%, that's 25%.
David Mendenhall: Rule is 50%.
Wade: What rule?
Kostadis Roussos: And whether… No, and we went over this at the very beginning, 25th…
David Mendenhall: So…
Kostadis Roussos: here.
David Mendenhall: Okay, I don't understand.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it has to cover 50%, it can't just be, like, a touch.
David Mendenhall: Oh, well, forget it then.
Kostadis Roussos: You could get those, too.
David Mendenhall: No.
David Mendenhall: It's a waste.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: When you get a subclass to get Fireball?
David Mendenhall: Yeah.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I'm not very excited about the capabilities of this.
David Mendenhall: I'm frightened, so I can't attack.
Wade: You can attack, you just can't move closer, right?
David Mendenhall: I move closer. If I attack, I have disadvantage.
Gary Young: Are you frightened by the wolves, or the dire wolves, or both?
Kostadis Roussos: He's frightened by the… he's frightened the wolf… the wolves have caused the frightened condition.
Gary Young: So does that mean you can still attack the direwolf normally?
Wade: Just with disadvantage.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it has it as a disability.
David Mendenhall: have disadvantage.
Gary Young: Oh, like on all attacks?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Okay.
David Mendenhall: And I can't reach the dire wolf.
David Mendenhall: Yeah. Great.
Kostadis Roussos: Do the spell you were gonna do either way.
David Mendenhall: Well, I'm a little disappointed.
David Mendenhall: I've got… I've got very little here.
Gary Young: Throw a dagger?
Wade: Just take the disadvantage and deal with it?
Kostadis Roussos: Mr. Smockery on, the.
David Mendenhall: Werewolf, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Would roll the natural twin.
David Mendenhall: Alright, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You are no longer… no, no, that's not true.
David Mendenhall: No, that's not true.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry.
David Mendenhall: Remain frightened as long as they're alive.
Gary Young: Board.
Wade: You're working long.
Gary Young: 2, 3, 4…
Wade: Why is your error?
Gary Young: Fine.
Wade: iron?
Gary Young: 6.
Wade: It's got a stunt arrow.
Gary Young: Okay, so I'm going to attack 6, and then cleave into 4.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Can't cleave into the big guy?
Gary Young: Clean up all these little guys.
Wade: Okay.
Gary Young: And then immediately my attack button's not working.
Gary Young: What about that? Does that do anything? No?
Gary Young: Click.
Gary Young: Click order?
Gary Young: Double digits.
Gary Young: Okay, so it hits… for… 10 damage, Plus 2 rage.
Gary Young: So, that kills 6.
Gary Young: And then I will… Cleave into number 4.
Gary Young: And that does just simple weapon damage, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: for 9.
Kostadis Roussos: You did 9 points of… okay, so can you just mark the damage?
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the first…
Gary Young: Six. Six dies.
Kostadis Roussos: 6 dies?
Gary Young: Oh, and I forgot to do Fairy Fire on him, but… oh well.
Kostadis Roussos: Six dies?
Gary Young: And then… it was… Number 4 takes 9 damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you add your… you didn't add your, plus 2.
Kostadis Roussos: Enrage.
Gary Young: For what?
Kostadis Roussos: Are you raging or not raging?
Gary Young: Do I get rage with a cleave damage, too?
Kostadis Roussos: It's to every attack.
Gary Young: Okay, but I don't get my strength bonus on Cleave.
Kostadis Roussos: Off.
Gary Young: Don't attack.
Gary Young: is…
Gary Young: Yeah, that is, leave… warm…
Gary Young: Alright, I don't know if it applies or not.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, again, let me just check.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, add it.
Gary Young: Okay. That seems…
Kostadis Roussos: That seems to be the consensus.
Gary Young: Alright, so then it kills 4 as well.
Gary Young: Okay.
Gary Young: And then… I am… Adequately within, within,
Gary Young: Attack of opportunity if those little guys come close closer.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, who is up?
Wade: That was just Brewbarry, right? So it's all the wolves.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Literally all of them.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see which wolves are still alive, forgot to delete a few, so…
Gary Young: The forest dead.
Kostadis Roussos: 4 is dead, so that's 1, 3, and 5, right?
Gary Young: Yeah, so 3 is…
Wade: 35 and Dire.
Kostadis Roussos: What? Pardon me?
Gary Young: 3 is technically first.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so… 3 charges at you.
Gary Young: Yup, so I get an attack opportunity while he tries that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: Okay, that's a hit for… Fetal bench?
Kostadis Roussos: It's another dead one. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: The Barbarian… the Barbarian is getting a lot of pelts here.
Gary Young: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Dire.
Gary Young: Are they?
Wade: air trade pelts.
Gary Young: They are.
Gary Young: They attacked us first.
Kostadis Roussos: The Dire Wolf moves to you. Does that get… does that give you an attack of opportunity, or not?
Gary Young: I would have had an extra reaction?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't.
Wade: Yeah, I assume it's limited to one.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he takes a bite.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And knocks you prone for 8 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Unless you have a ability to resist prone.
Gary Young: while reaching… I am large.
Kostadis Roussos: You're large? In that case? No, he is not prone, you are not prone.
Gary Young: Yeah.
Gary Young: I mean, I guess I should technically be using a bigger mini, but .
Kostadis Roussos: That's fine, it's fine.
Wade: a maxi.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, one in.
Gary Young: Actually, if I'm using a bigger mini, that means that my reach is even broader, isn't it?
Wade: I would say yes.
Kostadis Roussos: I would say yes.
Gary Young: Yeah, it should be, like, a bigger mini.
Kostadis Roussos: I just… I just read something, we should all bow before our halberd overlords.
Wade: Oh, jeez.
Wade: 20 foot reach.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it's still 10-foot reach.
Kostadis Roussos: The halberd is still a halberd.
Kostadis Roussos: It's still a 10.
Gary Young: later levels.
Kostadis Roussos: It's not at this level, though.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: Actually, actually, hold on a second.
Gary Young: Are we level 3 yet?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Gary Young: Oh, okay. So, so I have Halberd, which is plus 5 reach, but I also have this… Giant's Havoc.
Gary Young: my reach increases by 5, so I actually have a 15-foot reach now.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that's good to know.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's, that's useful. I mean, that, like I said, we all bowed before our overlords.
Gary Young: Okay, I gotta keep… I gotta start playing that far from it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, you know, it's like, okay, so this guy attacks you, and this guy attacks you.
Kostadis Roussos: Since they're all within 5 feet of each other, they get to attack with advantage.
Kostadis Roussos: The first… what's your armor class?
Gary Young: 16.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let's see what the attack bonus on this character is, on the monster is. It's a plus 4, so that's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: And then 2B20, keep high 1 plus 4.
Kostadis Roussos: That's also a hit, so you take another 10 points of…
Kostadis Roussos: Nope, no, no, yes, you're 10 points of damage, that's it.
Gary Young: Total of 10. Have just 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, well, yeah, yeah, sample is 5. Alright.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade: Two's dead, isn't he? He's off the bar.
Kostadis Roussos: like this.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. I should have deleted that.
Gary Young: Is there a button you can press to make my mini large?
Gary Young: Okay, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just… I think I could do something here.
Gary Young: This is the War of the Giants.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: Off to Soma.
Wade: It looks like it's a full action to move the, moonbeam, and so I'm just gonna leave it there for now.
Wade: And we're going to chew on the dire wolf first.
Wade: So… That's not a kill.
Wade: So I've created a giant Brewbarry.
Gary Young: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: So you should be able to drag and drop that whenever you need.
Gary Young: Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Wade: Clause in… No, the second attack misses. Dang.
Kostadis Roussos: So you… who are you attacking?
Wade: That was the dire wolf.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So the Direwolf takes another 6 points of damage.
Wade: Down to 11.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you killed another one?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so we're down. Okay, so, because I see, the… that this wolf here has zero hit points, number.
Wade: Oh, that wasn't me, somebody else… That's, number 4.
Gary Young: 4 is already removed from the map, that's… it's okay.
Wade: 4's still on my map.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I… okay, yeah, so I think let's get… is there… is there a… there's only one wolf left, so let's get rid of him. Alright, he's gone.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Wade: I'm just… Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: We're down to one wolf.
Kostadis Roussos: Dave, you are no longer affected by the, terror.
Kostadis Roussos: The pack is gone.
Kostadis Roussos: Dave?
David Mendenhall: Really?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes, the pack is gone. It's been defeated.
Kostadis Roussos: There's no pack left. There's one wolf. A wolf of one pack is not a wolf.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Valphine?
David Mendenhall: Can I apply?
Gary Young: Sure.
David Mendenhall: No, no, it's Rickard and… Oh, okay, you should have waited until my turn. Alright, Milfino.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: 1… 2, 3, 4… Five?
David Mendenhall: You don't want to go through the moonbeam.
Gary Young: I went around it.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
Gary Young: 1, 2, 3.
Wade: Yeah, I… Yeah, I don't think it differentiates, it's just like any creature.
Wade: I guess I could have dropped it, but… sorry.
Gary Young: Let's see if my… Nope.
Gary Young: Cannot do this, usually.
Gary Young: Whoa…
Gary Young: That's a mess.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Gary Young: Booker in Europe.
David Mendenhall: Why is that not working?
David Mendenhall: What was that?
Gary Young: Just ignore that.
Wade: Heh.
Gary Young: It's like doing some stuff, it's just, like, not…
Gary Young: Letting me click the buttons on the page here.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, I'm not able to click on buttons either now.
David Mendenhall: I now also have the same problem.
Wade: Still working for me, but…
David Mendenhall: Hmm.
David Mendenhall: Okay.
David Mendenhall: 16 hits.
David Mendenhall: Yep.
Wade: Direwolf is… 14, yeah. 15 will hit.
Kostadis Roussos: I, I, okay, just so you know, today is September 2nd.
Kostadis Roussos: Apparently, there was a hotfix, they're… they're bug fixing.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, well, I need to keep working on it.
Kostadis Roussos: I just want you to know, I… I… the guy does… I did give him some money, so I will send him a note.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Gary Young: What, roll 20?
David Mendenhall: Okay, I did a total of 11 damage on the…
Wade: That'll take them out.
David Mendenhall: on the…
Kostadis Roussos: Terminous.
David Mendenhall: I'm the dire wolf, yeah.
Wade: I'll take them out. They're both at 11, so…
David Mendenhall: Okay, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: There's… alright, everybody's dead.
Wade: Yeah, there's one wolf left.
David Mendenhall: Brewbarry needs to take care of Wolf1.
Wade: No, let's make him a pet.
Gary Young: Tame him.
Wade: Bring back Scratch.
Gary Young: That is a miss.
Gary Young: Who's next?
Wade: Wolf.
Gary Young: Woof.
Gary Young: Haha!
Gary Young: Could be.
Gary Young: I'll growl at the wolf.
Kostadis Roussos: on World Fronts.
Gary Young: Well, I'll get sick.
David Mendenhall: Then he gets hit.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, he disengages and runs, so…
Gary Young: I've disengages.
David Mendenhall: Mmm.
David Mendenhall: Oh, we use Disengage.
Wade: Doesn't dash, yeah.
David Mendenhall: It doesn't manage.
Wade: Let him go.
David Mendenhall: Alright, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Gary Young: Is it a regular-looking wolf, or is it, like, a spectral wolf?
Wade: We've got those red eyes and shit, right?
Kostadis Roussos: It had, like, red eyes. So, you do find some pelts. Do you wish to remove the pelts?
David Mendenhall: That is Organic Fair Trade.
Wade: It's also blighted pelt, guys.
Gary Young: Well, we'll check it when we get… bring it back to town, and we'll see how…
David Mendenhall: I'm definitely taking the pelts.
Wade: You're gonna carry that blighted pelt with you. Yes.
Wade: I don't want that in my backpack, you guys do what you want.
Kostadis Roussos: how many.
Gary Young: lighting pulse we get, we get 5, regular and 1 dire.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: And I have to figure out how much that's worth, but let's just make a note that you have them.
David Mendenhall: You can put false for his blood. Wow, look at that.
Gary Young: Yeah. I rarely get to do that.
Kostadis Roussos: repeat.
Gary Young: See, see, we can turn this into, like,
Gary Young: A, a wolfskin, cloak of displacement.
David Mendenhall: There you go. Yeah, wow!
Kostadis Roussos: So I'm assuming… I'm assuming we're back to non-giant Brewbarry?
Gary Young: Yes, yes. I'll… I'll do that just to test that I know what I'm doing.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you can… I did it for you, so you can switch to Giant Brewbarry if you want.
Kostadis Roussos: You just drag him on there.
Gary Young: I'm just… I'm just testing. You do your thing.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I presume that you'll keep, heading deeper into this bizarre forest.
Wade: That's my plan.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, as you… okay, let me just get rid of this.
David Mendenhall: Not get lost.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I need to…
Wade: Sure, why not?
Kostadis Roussos: You did not get lost. Alright, there's one more.
Wade: Well, maybe I'll get lost on my own, just for fun.
Kostadis Roussos: One good, one bad.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: 19…
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Wade: Holding.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You suddenly stop… you suddenly… as you're walking through the forest, you step and you see a small, still pool.
Kostadis Roussos: And as Sue… look at it.
Kostadis Roussos: You don't see yourself, but twisted, distorted versions of yourselves, warped in anguish or joy.
Wade: Which one is it? Anguish or Joy?
Gary Young: in English.
Kostadis Roussos: Angry… okay. Yeah, well, it depends what you want.
Gary Young: So you're saying that Valphine sees a joy-ridden version of herself instead of an English-ridden one?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Sarah, that would bring her joy.
Gary Young: That's theory up.
Gary Young: Alright.
David Mendenhall: Anybody want to go for a swim?
Wade: You know, given that the trees attacked us? I don't know.
Wade: This is the center of the forest.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it's not, but you can sense… you can sense…
David Mendenhall: How many hit points do I have?
Wade: It didn't take much. You took, like, one or two shots this time.
David Mendenhall: I'm at 16 hit points… Let's see, I'm gonna use a Bardic Inspiration… on myself…
David Mendenhall: So if I fail a D20… I can benefit from it.
David Mendenhall: And, yeah, why not? I'll… I'll…
David Mendenhall: I'll get in the pool, sure. I'm lucky I would have done it.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, did you jump in the pool?
David Mendenhall: Unlucky would have done it.
David Mendenhall: He's not here.
David Mendenhall: Oh, for Jarek.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, for Jarek…
Kostadis Roussos: You jump in the pool, and it's kind of like… have you seen that scene in the Marvel Universe?
David Mendenhall: Okay, so basically, it's like a series of mirrors, all sort of…
Kostadis Roussos: reflecting… people, scenes, faces at you all at the same time. Okay. Roll a… intelligence saving throw.
Wade: Just the one who jumped in?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's just the one who jumped in.
David Mendenhall: When the creature fails a D20, the creature… okay.
David Mendenhall: Alright, so Intelligence Save.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, DYT14.
David Mendenhall: Okay, let's see what I get.
David Mendenhall: You get an 8. Now, hang on, it's not over yet.
David Mendenhall: You said I need a 14?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
David Mendenhall: I have a 1 in 6 chance of making it.
David Mendenhall: Let's see…
David Mendenhall: I got a 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you don't notice anything, but you do gain a level of madness. Do you want to keep looking around?
David Mendenhall: Level of madness?
Wade: This just turned into, a Call of Cthulhu.
Gary Young: Bye.
David Mendenhall: sadness.
Kostadis Roussos: Ugh.
David Mendenhall: Hang on… I'm… I'm contemplating my options.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, sure, why don't I… I'll use a bonus action to take another Bardic inspiration, and then, sure, I'll stick around.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: Want me to roll again?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes?
David Mendenhall: 12… And… 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Gary Young: Does the madness give him a genius, inspiration, and…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
David Mendenhall: I need to compose something right now.
Wade: This'll work!
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Gary Young: Maybe it'll mesh nicely with the Velfe.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll a D6, roll a D6.
David Mendenhall: Roll a D6.
David Mendenhall: Alright.
David Mendenhall: 2.
Kostadis Roussos: He… and you see… you see a distorted…
Kostadis Roussos: creature, human, you can't really tell
Kostadis Roussos: Pleading. He saw beyond, but only what he was meant to see. The numbers. Always the numbers.
Gary Young: It's true, it's always the numbers.
David Mendenhall: Oh, helpful!
David Mendenhall: Alright, I think I've tested my luck enough. I'm out.
David Mendenhall: And, my madness, do you want me to roll for effect?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, roll a D100.
David Mendenhall: All the D100 and see what happens.
Gary Young: Afraid of music.
David Mendenhall: I need to compose something right now.
David Mendenhall: 95… Falls unconscious.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Cool.
Kostadis Roussos: No, when he exits the pool.
Kostadis Roussos: He exits the pool and just collapses.
Wade: It's like, is he gonna drown? That's not so bad. You guys can, like, wake me up or something. Right. Just carry you on my bareback, whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So yes, there's… there's definitely… you did get the impression that this was some…
Kostadis Roussos: Do you describe it to your friends, do they want to roll Arcana checks?
David Mendenhall: Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure, once I'm… once I wake up, I suppose.
Wade: How long is that gonna be?
David Mendenhall: Just, you slap him, he wakes up.
Wade: Oh, okay, just in…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Gary Young: I rolled an Arkita check.
Kostadis Roussos: Fuck you!
Wade: Brewbarry, just…
David Mendenhall: Hey, I can match that number!
Wade: Add us together, and it's Phil Brewbarry.
Kostadis Roussos: We've had brew… like, I… can I show.
David Mendenhall: Super Bowl.
Kostadis Roussos: I don'.
David Mendenhall: Arcane attack, Jesus.
Kostadis Roussos: Can I just say something? I don't know what it is with barbarians in this party rolling absurd dice on…
Kostadis Roussos: Is there…
Gary Young: It's the hotfix, they need to fix that shit.
David Mendenhall: Alright, Brewbarry, tell us what it meant. You're an expert on numbers, aren't you?
Gary Young: Yes. I can count all the way to 4.
David Mendenhall: 1, 2, 4.
Wade: Three, sir.
Kostadis Roussos: So, what you… so, Brewbarry has heard legends of these pools.
Gary Young: Yes.
Gary Young: I've heard of these pools, they were…
Kostadis Roussos: Where, where people…
Gary Young: the lore of the Oathcourt Barbarians, and…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's good. And so, the key thing about these pools is that they are… Shadows to other places.
Kostadis Roussos: And that they appear unnaturally.
Gary Young: Basically, it's…
Kostadis Roussos: It's a… No, what you remember is that they would appear, and then disappear.
Kostadis Roussos: And that if you looked into them, you could learn
Kostadis Roussos: You, you, you had never experienced this, so this was all, secondhand, that you could…
Kostadis Roussos: If you looked at them, you could find yourself and ask yourself some questions.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So, so you jumped into the…
Gary Young: questions?
Kostadis Roussos: You jumped into the pool, so you got whatever happened, right? I was expecting that. But apparently, if you look into it, Brewbarry says you can see yourself and ask yourself a question.
Gary Young: Alright, I'm ready to ask my question.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you're gonna go do that? Alright, roll your wisdom saving throw.
David Mendenhall: Your intelligence signature, rather, your intelligence signature.
Gary Young: Apologies?
Wade: Should be a good minus on that, I hope.
Gary Young: Should I ask my question first, or should I roll my… Vice versa.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, do whatever you want.
Kostadis Roussos: What side of the bread should I butter?
David Mendenhall: Price Brewbarry.
Wade: Wow.
David Mendenhall: I go mad trying to figure that one out.
Kostadis Roussos: Why?
Wade: There's a raven like a writing desk.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, the, the, the, the, the, the,
Kostadis Roussos: What a Brewbarry sees is a version of Brewbarry that butters both sides simultaneously.
Wade: More butter!
Kostadis Roussos: It's like…
Gary Young: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, roll your, roll your, short-term madness effect.
Wade: This right here, this is why I'm a naturalist. That shit ain't natural, and it's messing you guys up.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you, you, you start, you start running away.
Gary Young: Okay.
Wade: Man!
Kostadis Roussos: Does somebody want to try to grapple him, or…
Wade: Can I just, like, pounce on him?
Gary Young: Maybe a bear can…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, all right. All right, I will, I will assume you, you, you, you, you guys, run.
Wade: If anybody could grapple them, it'd be me.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so you bounce on top of him.
Kostadis Roussos: I will just assume that, Brewbarry has been grappled, he is terrified, minutes elapse.
Gary Young: Unfortunately, I have advantage on grapple.
Wade: Do it.
David Mendenhall: unresistant.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay, so we could do this a few times. Roll, let's keep rolling. Alright, fine, we're gonna do a pursuit, we're gonna do a chase.
Gary Young: Oh, I rolled pretty bad. That's good.
Kostadis Roussos: What did you do?
Wade: ranked, or what?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, strength or, acrobatics or athletics.
Wade: Oh, acrobatic here, though. I'm not really good at either, so… Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Fair, though you should be good at.
Wade: I don't… I don't get extra abilities that I see. I do… oh, I do… I guess Acrobatics is decks, so I get a plus zero anyway, yeah, that's fine.
Gary Young: Well, I do win that fight.
Wade: Stay down, Brewbarry, this is for your own good.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I was gonna go do the chase rules, but, you know…
Wade: Bear wins.
Kostadis Roussos: Bear wins. Right. Brutberry's kind of, like, screaming about, you know…
Gary Young: I'm proud of you!
Wade: There's no right side.
Kostadis Roussos: I suppose.
Kostadis Roussos: That's actually not what it said, but, you know, that's what you think you saw.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Gary Young: Alright, so Valphine will ask a more intelligent question.
Wade: Guys, stop!
Wade: For your own sanity!
Gary Young: Aren't we supposed to ask questions about, like, how to close this?
David Mendenhall: I can just cast Lesser Restoration on them, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, shoot.
David Mendenhall: I have to touch him for that, don't I?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Well, if you're touching them, you can, you know.
David Mendenhall: I want to burn a spell on this.
Kostadis Roussos: Miss.
David Mendenhall: If we're… if we're having trouble grappling him, are we having trouble?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, blueberries is… is… is… we're, like, at some point in time, Brewbarry just stops a minute later.
Wade: underway to bear.
Kostadis Roussos: Brewbarry's trying to explain to Valphine, to Soma, the importance of… that it's not one side, but both sides.
Gary Young: Alright, alright.
Wade: Good, good barbarian.
Kostadis Roussos: Both sides. Soba, not one. Both sides.
Wade: I understand. We'll get you both sides of your bread. We'll cut the crusts off, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yeah.
Gary Young: But I assume this has something to do with, like, how we, you know, the source of this, this thing, and so therefore we should still be interacting with it? Yes?
David Mendenhall: You can come back.
Wade: I don't…
Kostadis Roussos: Come back.
David Mendenhall: Let's go to the center. Anyway, what was…
Gary Young: It's about the Senate.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, it's not the center, the center is.
Wade: We're not at the center yet.
David Mendenhall: Not at the center of the forest yet.
Gary Young: Oh, okay, alright.
Wade: One by one, I'm watching my compatriots go mad, so, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: So do you guys, wait to get to… I presume you're going to…
Wade: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Go to the center.
David Mendenhall: Let's head to the center.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Wade: Yeesh.
Wade: That looks like a good place to stop.
Kostadis Roussos: This is a good… Great place to stop.
Gary Young: And there's more of those wells, huh?
David Mendenhall: Oh, there are.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so…
Wade: Matt, to your heart's content.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so these are… so yes, the point here was so that you know what these…
Wade: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, these are all wells, the, the… just so we're…
Wade: Wait, they're all wells, or just the blue ones are wells?
Kostadis Roussos: Abyss as a well. Sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: That's great.
Wade: Oh, those… the… the sunspots or whatever?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that was what the icon was supposed to be, I just… anyway.
Wade: I… yeah, I get ya. I will.
David Mendenhall: Which, which… Well, if we go in from the northwest, looks like we can avoid the brambles.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Anyway, so we will… we'll discuss it, and I… I will… we will… I just… yes, you arrive here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to be going from the north? I mean, you can pick which… I'll just drop you.
David Mendenhall: Yeah, looks like we want to come in from the northwest to avoid the brambles.
Kostadis Roussos: And I didn't put these here, but you also see a druid… And 2…
Kostadis Roussos: Folks who look like rangers caught in the bramble.
Wade: No, the first party.
David Mendenhall: Oh, well, once we save them, then they can do the battle.
Wade: Excellent.
Wade: And we can go get all the credit.
David Mendenhall: Put them in the front.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, exactly. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And, and when they, they, they do look…
Kostadis Roussos: That's the word I'm looking for?
Wade: wish.
Kostadis Roussos: well, definitely Druidish. But definitely, you know, Soma recognizes them as members of the Emerald Enclave.
David Mendenhall: Well, it's a great time to get some more allies!
David Mendenhall: We're all gonna be partying, playing music together, and this is all over.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Wade: Listening to your music together.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I will… Exit here.
David Mendenhall: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright guys, see you next week.